

Curriculum vitae

PERSONAL INFORMATION Gaetano Settembre



- 💎 Via Pietro Micca, 78 70024, Gravina in Puglia (BA), Italy
- (+39) 333 40 76 393
- gaetanosettembre@gmail.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/gaetano-settembre/
- D ORCID 0000-0002-0592-8575

Gender Male | Date of birth 11 January 1996 | Nationality Italian

About me

Post Graduated Data Science student. IT and data enthusiast with an interest in Data Analysis, Machine Learning, and full-stack development.

Passionate about new technology learning, exploration and engineering with strong interpersonal skills and auto didactic tendencies. I've developed a particular interest in research during my internship at Institute of Crystallography, in which I have written my thesis. I would love to advance my understanding multi/hyperspectral data analysis further, through PhD study and with experts in the field.

WORK ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Oct 2021 – Mar 2022 Curricular Internship

Institute of Crystallography c/o CNR

Via Giovanni Amendola, 122/O - 70126, Bari, Italy

- ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) process of crystallographic data from open source databases
- Exploratory analysis of crystallographic data and non-parametric statistical tests
- Training, evaluation and tuning of ML (Machine Learning) models for crystal system determination (multi-class classification task)
- High-performance Models Deployment and development of Web Platform called CrystalMELA (Crystallography MachinE LeArning) [2]

Nov 2018 – Apr 2019 Curricular Internship

SER&Practices (SER&P)

Via Edoardo Orabona, 4 - 70125, Bari, Italy

- Development of "Serious games" following the Red Team vs. Blue Team approach to improve the skills of the SOC (Security Operation Center) and CSRIT (Computer Security Incident Response Team) team
- Development of malicious attack scenarios on Linux Servers and Web Applications with the intention of extracting sensitive data using the Cyber Kill Chain framework
- Penetration Test and Vulnerability Assessment
- Data collection, data analysis (logs, alerts, etc.) and reporting using the IBM Security QRadar SIEM

EDUCATION

Oct 2019 — Mar 2022 Master's Degree in Data Science (LM-91)

University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Department of Computer Science, Italy

Final grade: Full mark with honors - 110/110 & Lode (highest possible grade in the Italian system).

"Analisi di dati cristallografici e costruzione di modelli predittivi". Supervisors: Prof. Nicoletta Thesis:

Del Buono; Dr. Rosanna. Rizzi, Dr. Nicola Corriero

PA Code: 02-0000681044-0002282158

Sep 2015 — Apr 2019 Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (L-31)

University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Department of Computer Science, Italy

Thesis: Red Team vs Blue Team: Data Exflitration in Government". Supervisor: Prof. Danilo Caivano



PA Code: 02-0000681044-0002288080

Aug 2010 — Jul 2015 High School for Scientific Studies

High School "G. Tarantino", Applied Science/s curricula, Gravina in Puglia, Italy

	High School "G. Tarantino", Applied Science/s curricula, Gravina in Puglia, Italy		
CERTIFICATIONS AND COURSES			
Apr 2022	 Machine Learning with Python Certificate ID Number: 968f2ab5ed844758b714235e98b5e287 	IBM	
	- Deep Learning Essentials	IBM	
	Certificate ID Number: 14c4279c8c934daa825c07eb61df8587		
Oct 2021	, , ,	IBM	
	Certificate ID Number: caf35b5e29d44ab4a5239bfd607fd182 – Data Visualization using Python	IBM	
	Certificate ID Number: 0355a89d6c694ed8bc46eb00e9112452 – Data Science Methodologies	IBM	
	Certificate ID Number: acef4f90bcbe449782e429a1146a2a49 – Data Science Foundations - Level 1 and 2 (V2)	IBM	
	Certificate ID Number: c429ffdd4c3e470185e528830c3e1e35	IDIVI	
May 2020	 Corso "Sicurezza e Tutela della salute dei lavoratori" (Generale) Certificate Code: ojMByztiAg 	University of Bari	
Dec 2019	- Basic Course GDPR Regulation 679/2016 Certificate Code: 7cb536a6-6a41-49d6-ac84-e723fc7339ac	Dati360.it - Legal Suite	
Jul 2019	- 2-day QRadar BP Technical Enablement course	IBM and SERLAB	
Sep 2018	- English Assessment (Internal certification)	University of Bari	
May 2013	- European Computer Driving Licence (ECDL) Full Standard Certificate Certificate Code: IT 1969501, Skill Card: 1969501		
Info:	All badges of verified achievements from IBM are available at the following link: https://www.credly.com/users/gaetano-settembre/badges (Credly profile).		
NETWORKS AND MEMBERSHIP			
Oct 2021 – Current	Mathematics In Data AnalysiS - (Midas) research group at the University of Bari "Aldo Moro", Italy, currently coordinated by Prof. N. Del Buono.		
Jun 2019 — Current	2hands Organization volunteer. Environmental protection through cleanups, innovative projects and awareness raising.		
Jan 2014 – Current	Federazione Italiana Pallacanetro - (FIP), basketball referee (Id. A056193).		
HONOURS AND AWARDS			
Oct 2020	Referee authorized to officiate "Serie C Gold" (men) and "Serie B" (women) basketball games.		
Oct 2018	Referee authorized to officiate "Serie C Silver" basketball matches.		
Sep 2016	Regional referee authorized to officiate "Serie D" basketball games.		

Oct 2013 Institute representative - High School "G. Tarantino".

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Italian

Curriculum vitae

Other languages

Mother tongue

UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production	
B1	B2	B1	B1	B1

English

English Assessment (Internal certification) issued by University of Bari

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user – B1 and B2: Independent user – C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

DIGITAL SKILLS

Languages Python, Java, JavaScript, C/C++, R, MATLAB, HTML, PHP, CSS, LaTeX

Database MySQL, PostgreSQL + PostGIS, MongoDB, Neo4j

Versioning Git, SVN

Data Science scikit-learn, numpy, pandas, tensorflow, pytorch, matplotlib, seaborn, Tableau, Apache Spark,

spaCy, NLTK, Data mining e machine learning: Knime, Weka, Orange

E Visual Studio / Visual Studio Code, PyCharm, Eclipse, NetBeans, RStudio, Jupyter, Google

Colab

Applications Microsoft Office Suite, Collaborative tools (Trello, Slack, Microsoft Teams), AutoCAD 2D/3D

OSs Windows, Unix Linux

OTHER INFORMATION

Driving licence B

PUBLICATIONS

 Machine Learning approaches for predicting Crystal Systems: a brief review and a case study

Paper ID: 1091, to appear on Proceeding of 8th International Conference on Machine Learning, Optimization, and Data Science – LOD 2022 – September 18–22, Certosa di Pontignano (Siena), Tuscany, Ed(s) Giuseppe Nicosia, Panos Pardalos, Lecture Notes in Computer Science, 2022, Springer, Cham, ISSN: 0302-9743 (print); 1611-3349 (web).

For this publication, the publisher's offcial letter of acceptance is attached.

[2] CrystalMELA: A new Crystallography MachinE LeArning platform for crystal system determination

Article submitted to Journal of Applied Crystallography (IUCr), ISSN: 1600-5767. Technical report, 1/22, Department of Mathematics, Bari, Italy,18 July 2022.

Gravina in Puglia (BA) - 18 Jul, 2022

Gaetano Settembre

Solte Settembre

In compliance with the GDPR and the Italian Legislative Decree no. 196 dated 30/06/2003, I hereby authorize you to use and process my personal details contained in this document.